Guide to the Poetry: A Magazine of Verse Records 1895-1961
University of Chicago Library
Poetry: A Magazine of Verse. Records
1895-1961
100 linear feet (174 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
Poetry: A Magazine of Verse was founded in Chicago, Illinois in 1912 by Harriet Monroe. The collection contains the administrative records of Poetry: A Magazine of Verse from its founding in 1912 to 1961, and documents not only the history of the magazine, but also the development of English-language verse in the first half of the twentieth century. The administrative files include correspondence, poetry, articles and reviews sent to and compiled by each editor of the magazine. Also included are a smaller number of business and editorial files, containing financial and fund raising records, literary prizes, author biographies, clippings and other items documenting the operation of the magazine.
Information on Use
Access
No restrictions.
Historical Note
Poetry: A Magazine of Verse was founded in 1912 by Chicago poet Harriet Monroe. Taking Whitman's line, "To have great poets there must be great audiences too" as her motto, Monroe sought to cultivate a wide readership for new writing and ideas. By insisting on paying all contributors and establishing an annual prize, Poetry magazine raised the visibility and status of poetry. The journal published and promoted the careers of a galaxy of poets who came to define twentieth century modernism, including T. S. Eliot, Ezra Pound, Marianne Moore, Wallace Stevens, William Carlos Williams, Robert Frost, and Langston Hughes, among many others. Poetry transformed the way that poetry and poets are recognized and read worldwide, and it continues to flourish as a major cultural influence.
Monroe funded the early publication of Poetry with subscriptions and contributions from wealthy Chicago patrons. As editor, she shepherded the magazine through into its third decade. Following Monroe's death in 1936, editorship passed to Morton Dauwen Zabel (1936-1937), followed by George Dillon (1937-1949), Hayden Carruth (acting editor, 1949), Karl Shapiro (1950-1954) and Henry Rago (1955-1969).
In 1931, Harriet Monroe presented her poetry library, her personal papers, and the editorial files of Poetry magazine to the University of Chicago. Following her death, the Monroe library and Poetry archives were received as a bequest and installed in a specially designated room in Wieboldt Hall, the modern languages building on the campus of the University of Chicago. The Modern Poetry Library room provided book shelves for the poetry collection, display cases for the letters and manuscripts of notable poets in the Poetry archives, and equipment for listening to recordings of poets reading their works.
The formal opening of the Harriet Monroe Library of Modern Poetry was marked by a festive dinner of the University of Chicago Friends of the Library on May 24, 1938. Guest speakers paying tribute to Harriet Monroe's achievements included Carl Sandburg, Archibald MacLeish, Ford Maddox Ford, George Dillon, and Sterling North. Messages lauding Monroe's remarkable influence were received from many of the poets she had encouraged and promoted, including Ezra Pound, Walter De La Mare, William Rose Benet, Witter Bynner, John Gould Fletcher, Edgar Lee Masters, Lew Sarett, Jean Starr Untermeyer, and John Hall Wheelock, among others.
In addition to the gift of her library and archives, Harriet Monroe's will provided $5,000 to establish a fund for the advancement and encouragement of poetry through the award of a $500 prize for distinction in poetry. Monroe stipulated that the committee of award for the prize should give preference to "poets of progressive rather than academic tendencies." The inaugural Harriet Monroe Poetry Award, given at the University of Chicago in June 1941, was presented to twenty-eight-year-old Muriel Rukeyser. Among those receiving the award in later years were Marianne Moore, Wallace Stevens, and Robert Lowell.
In 1953, the Harriet Monroe Modern Poetry Library was incorporated within the newly established Department of Special Collections of the University of Chicago Library. In 2002, this department became the Special Collections Research Center. The Modern Poetry book collection, enlarged continuously on an annual basis with the support of an endowed acquisition fund, is divided between a poetry collection in the general stacks of Regenstein Library and the Modern Poetry rare books and serials in the Special Collections Research Center. The editorial archives of Poetry magazine, the personal papers of Harriet Monroe, and the papers of other modern poets, editors and publishers of poetry are held as part of the manuscript collections in the Special Collections Research Center.
The editorial archives of Poetry: A Magazine of Verse acquired by bequest from Harriet Monroe included extensive files of correspondence and poetry manuscripts from the time of her founding of the journal in 1912 until her death in 1936. Subsequently, the University of Chicago Library acquired two additional series of editorial files documenting Poetry and its authors during the years 1936-1953 and 1954-1961. Together, these three series of files preserve the letters and writings of a significant and remarkably diverse group of modern poets of the first half of the twentieth century. Eliot, Pound, Williams, Moore, Yeats, Sandburg, Thomas, and Frost are represented, along with Vachel Lindsay, Conrad Aiken, Wallace Stevens, Yvor Winters, Sara Teasdale, James Joyce, Edgar Lee Masters, Alfred Kreymborg, Ford Maddox Ford, Louis Zukofsky, Hart Crane, Witter Bynner, and Robert Penn Warren, Richard Wilbur, and many others.
Scope Note
This collection contains administrative records of Poetry: A Magazine of Verse from its founding in 1912 to 1961. The majority of the files include correspondence, poetry, articles and reviews that were sent to and compiled by each editor of the magazine beginning with its first editor and founder, Harriet Monroe. Though the collection covers the period 1912 to 1961, it includes a small amount of correspondence from the late 1890s.
In the 1970s, the collection was first archivally organized into three series, based upon the original arrangement in which the papers were received. The preservation and microfilming project conducted in 2001-2002 retained this broad arrangement but also provided enhanced description by identifying subdivisions with each of the series. The Poetry collection has been arranged as follows: Series I: Administrative Files, 1912-1936, Series II: Administrative Files, 1936-1953, Series III: Administrative Files, 1954-1961 and Series IV: Oversize. For more descriptive information see the series descriptions for each series.
The collection documents not only the administration and growth of Poetry magazine, but also the development of English-language verse in the first half of the twentieth century. Most of the files within each series contain editorial correspondence and poetry, articles and reviews, in manuscript and proof form.
Each series contains a modest amount of business files having to do with the operation of the magazine including financial, advertising and fund raising records, literary prizes, author biographies and clippings.
Within each series, manuscripts and correspondence have generally been arranged alphabetically by the name of the author. Series I and II are divided into alphabetical subseries distinguished "Major" and "Minor" Poets, a division present in the files upon their receipt.
Related Resources
The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:
Browse finding aids by topic.
The editorial files of Poetry are amplified by collections of papers and records that document the work of individual poets and the publication of their writings. These materials include the papers of Harriet Monroe, Harriet Brainard Moody, Ronald Lane Latimer, Amy Bonner, and Morton D. Zabel, and the editorial files of the Chicago Review. Collections documenting the writing and publishing of modern poetry continue to be acquired.
Subject Headings
Monroe, Harriet, 1860-1936; Poetry. A Magazine of Verse; Poets, American; Poets, English; American poetry -- 20th century -- History and criticism; English poetry -- 20th century -- History and criticism; Poetry -- Periodicals
INVENTORY
- Series I: Administrative Files, 1912-1936
  Series I includes correspondence, manuscripts of poetry, articles and reviews sent to Harriet Monroe during her tenure as editor of Poetry: a Magazine of Verse. The manuscripts cover the period from the beginnings of the magazine to her death in 1936. This series has been divided into three subseries, reflecting the organization of the files as used by the editorial staff of the magazine. 1. General Manuscripts, 2. Major Poets, and 3. Addenda.
  Subseries 1, General Manuscripts contains alphabetically arranged correspondence and manuscripts submitted to Harriet Monroe, editor of Poetry. There is a limited amount of overlap between the first and second subseries. Cross-references have been added in many instances, but researchers are encouraged to review each series and subseries for related information.
  Subseries 2, Major Poets is arranged alphabetically. It includes editorial correspondence, manuscripts of poetry and prose and galleys, some with manuscript corrections.
  Subseries 3, Addenda, contains a mix of business records. It includes business correspondence; correspondence between Harriet Monroe and Poetry’s business manager, Mila Straub; biographical information provided by poets; guarantor’s records; circulars, news clippings; and photographs of Harriet Monroe. A small group of letters are identified as Crank Letters. These includes a miscellany, some marked "amusing" or "museum verses not for publication."
  - Subseries 1: General Manuscripts
    - Aannestad, G. Abbe, J. Abbe, Abbott, Aber, Abernathy, Achlandt, Ackley (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ackerman, Acton (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Adamic, E.L. Adams, F. Adams, J. Donald Adams, J.J. Adams, K.N. Adams, Adamson, F.H. Adler (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - H. Adler, Adriansen, Agcaoili, Ahern, Akins, Alandra (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Alden, Alderson, C.T. Alexander, H.B. Alexander, Alford, Ali (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - D. Allan, E.A. Allen, E.P. Allen, G. Allen (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - H. Allen, L.W. Allen, Allinson, Allott, Alsberg, Alstyne (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Julia Cooley Altrocchi (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Alvey, Alvord (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Alyea, American Academy in Rome (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - L.P. Ames, M. Ames, P. Ames, V.M. Ames (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - W. Ames, Andelson, E. Anderson, F. Anderson (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - J.B. Anderson, M. Anderson, M.B. Anderson, M.S. Anderson (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - G.E. Andrews, G.L. Andrews, M. Andrews, R. Angel, R. Angers (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - F.R. Angus, P.W. Angus, Aono, Applebaum, (Aquinas SEE Thomas Aquinas) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Arbuckle, K.R. Archer, W. Archer, Arens, Arensberg, D. Arkin, Armfield (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - A.J. Armstrong, M.B. Armstrong (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - M.D. Armstrong, M.M. Armstrong, J.B. Arnold, Arnstein (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Asbury (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Asch, Asenjo, Ashleigh, J. Ashley, W. Ashley, Askew, Atkins(W. Ashley SEE ALSO OVERSIZE) (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Joseph Auslander (SEE ALSO OVERSIZE) (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - G. Austin, J. Austin, M.H. Austin, Au-Young, Axson, Aydelotte (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Florence Ayscough (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - G. Bacon, I. Bacon, L. Bacon, Baer, Bafalgette, L.E. Bailey, M. Bailey, Bain (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - K.W. Baker, L.R. Baker, M.K. Baker, O. Baker, Balcom, Baldensperger (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - A.R. Baldwin, E.C. Baldwin, M. Baldwin, Ball, Ballantyne, Ballou, Baner (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Bangs, Banks, Banning, J. Barber (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - M.F. Barber, S.R. Barber (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Barclay, Bardin, E. Barker, M. Barker (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Mary Barnard (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - D. Barnes, F. Barnes, I. Barnes, Barnett, Barnette, Barney, Baron, Barratt, Barrerre, Barret (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Katherine E. Barrett (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Mary Barrett (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Wilton Agnew Barrett (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
    - Barrington, Barron, Barrows, Barrus, Barry, Barthibemy, A.H. Bartlett, F. Bartlett, F.D. Bartlett, H. Bartlett (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - P.A. Bartlett, R.M. Bartlett, T.H. Bartlett, Bartley, E.S. Barton, M.E. Barton, W.A. Barton, W.E. Barton (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Barzun, Basa, A. Bass, C.T. Bass, A.F. Bassett, G. Bassett, Batcheller, C.F. Bates (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - E. Bates, K.L. Bates, Battenhouse, Baumstone, Baveja, B. Baxter, S. Baxter, Bayfield (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Joseph Warren Beach (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
    - Beal, Beard, Beardsly, Beater, Beattie, Beaty (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Beaudoin, Beck (Beck SEE ALSO OVERSIZE) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - C. Becker, H. Becker, L. Becker, M.L. Becker, Beckwith, Bedell, Beecher, Beer, Beffel, Beghtol, Behn (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Beinhacker, Belden (Beinhacker SEE ALSO OVERSIZE) (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Ben Belitt (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - John Belknap (Box 2, Folder 10-12)
    - Bell, Bellamann, Bellamy, Benares, A. Bender, V. Bender, Bendon, L. Benedict, R.F. Benedict (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Benesh, I. Benjamin, P.L. Benjamin, A.E. Bennett, D. Bennett, M.B. Bennett, R. Bennett, Benson (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Bentley, Benton, Berens, A. Berman, B. Berman, Bernhard, Bernhardt, L. Berry (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - R. Berry, W. Berry, Beswick, Bethell, C. Betts, [?] Betts, L. Betts, T.J. Betts, Beuick (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Beverley, Beyers, Beynon, Bialk (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Biddle, Bidlach, Biller, Binkley, Binyon, Birch (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Laura Lee Bird (Box 2, Folder 19-21)
    - Birnsting, Bishop (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Bispham, J. Black, M. Black, Blackpool (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Blackwell, Blagden, A. Blair, G. Blair, H. Blake, J.V. Blake (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Blakeston, Blakey, Bland, Blanden, Blanding, Blaney (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Blank, Blankner, Blanton, Bliss (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Blitzstein, Bloch, L.J. Block, R. Block, Bloomhill, E. Blum (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - J. Blum, Blumenthal, (Bodenheim SEE G. MacDonald), Boeke, Bohr, Boillotat, Bois, Bolles, Bomburger (Boeke SEE OVERSIZE) (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Bond, Bone, Boner, Bonilla (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Bonn, Bontwell, Boogher, Boone (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Booth, Boothe, Bopes, Borden, Bordwell, Borie (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Borland, Bostelman, Bostwick, Boswell (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Botkin, Boutelle, M. Bowen, S. Bowen, Bowers, Bowles, E.W. Bowman, H.A. Bowman (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Louise Morey Bowman (Box 2, Folder 34-35)
    - A.C. Boyd, E.A. Boyd (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Polly Chase Boyden (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - K.B. Boyle, K.E. Boyle, V.F. Boyle, L. Boynton, P.H. Boynton (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Braddock, Bradford, F. Bradley, J.D. Bradley, M.H. Bradley, W. Bradley, W.A. Bradley, Bradshaw (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Bragdon, Bragg, Bragin (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Braithwaite, Branch (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Millen Brand (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
    - Brandon, Branson, Bray, Brearley, Bregy, Brenton, Brett, Brewster (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Bridges, Bridgman, Bridson, Brigham (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Bright, C.R. Brink, R.W. Brink, Brion, Brittain, Britten, Brittin, Britton (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - E.K. Broadus, K.H. Broadus, Brody, B.G. Brooks (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - E. Brower, J. Brower, A. Brown, A.V. Brown, C.I. Brown, E. Brown (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - G.I. Brown, S.A. Brown, S.M. Brown, T.B.R. Brown, T.M. Brown, W.L. Brown, A. Browne, C.F. Browne (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Maurice Browne (SEE ALSO OVERSIZE) (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Baker Brownell (Box 3, Folder 16-18)
    - H. Brownell, Brownrigg, Bruncken, Brush, H. Bryant, L. Bryant (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Oscar Brynes (SEE ALSO OVERSIZE) (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Bryson, Buchanan, H. Buck, M.F. Buck, Budd, Bugbee, Bullock (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Bump, Burger, R.L. Burgess, S.F. Burgess, Burgh, F. Burke, G. Burke, Burklund, Burlin, Burman, Burnham, A. Burns, C.M. Burns (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Stanley Burnshaw (Box 3, Folder 23-24)
    - Burnstein, Burr, Burrill, Burroughs, Burt, R. Burton, W.W. Burton, G.E. Bush (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - W. Bush, Bushby, Buss, C.M. Butcher, F. Butcher, A.C. Butler, G. Butler, J.S. Butler (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Butterworth, Buttitta, Button, Butts, Buzzell, Byington, Byrne (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Cades, Cady, Cafagna, Caffrey, Caie, Cairns, D. Caldwell, N. Caldwell (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Call, Calland, Callwell, Camerino (includes note from Ezra Pound), Cameron, A. Campbell, D. Campbell, Doris Campbell (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Gladys Campbell (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - H.S. Campbell, I.J. Campbell, J.W. Campbell, N. Campbell (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - W.S. Campbell (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Campione, H. S. Canby, M. Canby, Candelarias, Candler, Cane, Canfield (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Louise Gebhard Cann (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Skipwith Cannell (F1 includes note from Ezra Pound) (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - Cannon, Cantor (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Carden, Cardozo (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Carleton, Carlie (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Carlin, Carmer (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - A.M. Carpenter, J.A. Carpenter, M. Carpenter, D. Carr, F. Carr, L.D. Carr, Carrington, Carroll (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - D. Carter, L.A. Carter, Carus (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Cary, Case, Casement, Casements (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Cassidy, Castelein (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Jean Catel (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Caughey, Cavin, Cawein, Cesaresco (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Chadwick, Chagy, Challiss, G.K. Chalmers, R.T. Chalmers, Chamberlain, H.T. Chambers, R. Chambers (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Champney, Channing (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Helen B. Chapin (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - K.G. Chapin, Chapman, Charasson, J.D. Chase, J.E. Chase, M.M. Chase (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - P. Chase, P.A. Chase, Chattopadhyaya, Chen, A.C. Cheney, J.V.Cheney, S.Cheney, Cheng (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Cher, Cheverton, Cheyne, Cheyney, Childe, Chittick, Chown, Choyce (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Christenson, Christoph, Chrysler, Chubb (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Peggy Pond Church (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - R. Church, Churchill, Cianfoni, Ciolkowska, Citkowitz, Clairmont, Clampitt, Clancy (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Clapp, A.D.B. Clark (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - B. Clark, E. Clark, E.W. Clark, H.B. Clark, L. Clark, M. Clark, R.N. Clark, T.C. Clark (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - W.V. T. Clark, Clarke, Cleghorn, C. Clemens, J.R. Clemens, Clements (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Cleugh, Clevenger, Clifton, Cline, Clover, Clow, Clusman, Clute, A. A. Coates, F.E. Coates (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Grace Stone Coates (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Cobb, Coblentz, D.C. Cochran, E.J. Cochran (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - R.M. Cody, S. Cody, Coe, Cohen, Cohn, Colahan, N. Colby (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Cole, R.A. Coleman, R.R. Coleman, Colidge, D. Collins, L. Collins (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Columbia University, Colwell, Combs, Comfort, Comstock, Conant (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - G. Conklin, M. Conklin (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Connick, P. Conrad, S. Conrad, F.W. Cook (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Harold Lewis Cook (Box 4, Folder 33-34)
    - H. Cook, H.W. Cook, R.C. Cook, E.V. Cooke, F.J. Cooke, M.B. Cooke (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Le Baron Cooke (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - S. Bert Cooksley (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
    - Coolbrith, Cooley, Coomaraswamy, B.B. Cooper, Doris Cooper, Dorothy Cooper (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Coppard, Corbett, Corcoran, Cork, Cornelius (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Howard McKinley Corning (SEE ALSO OVERSIZE) (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
    - Cornish, Corrigan, D.M. Cory, R. Cory, Cosgrove, Costello, Costigan, Coughlin (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Coulson, Coulter, Cournos, Court, Cousins, Covell, Covici, Cowan, Cowden, Cowell (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Eleanor Rogers Cox (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Cozzens, A.T. Craig, M.N. Craig, Cramer, Crane, C. Cranmer (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - E.P. Cranmer, J.W. Crawford (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Nelson Antrim Crawford (Box 5, Folder 14-15)
    - Creagh, Creekmore, Cresson, Cressy, Crevequer, Crew (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Cribb, Crichton, Crist, Criswell, Crites, Crittenton, Cooke, Croft (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Cromwell, Cronyn (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Crook, Crosby (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - L. Cross, W. Cross, Crouch, F. Crow (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - M.F. Crow, Crowell, Crowninshield, Crozier (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Cughton, Culver, Cumberledge, Cumming, F. Cummings, P.H. Cummings, S.J. Cummings, Cummins (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Cunliffe, C. Cunningham, G.H. Cunningham, Curcio, Curran, Currey (Curran SEE ALSO OVERSIZE) (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - E. Curtis, L.A. Curtis, Cushing, Custer, Cuthbert, Cyr (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Daehn, Dagoret, Daguio, Dahlberg, Dahlgreen, Daline (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Dall, Dalton (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - James J. Daly (Box 5, Folder 27-28)
    - S.D. Daly, T.A. Daly, Dalziel (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - S. Foster Damon (Box 5, Folder 30-31)
    - Danby, Danforth, E.R.K. Daniels, F. Daniels, Danish, Dannenbaum (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - E.P. Dargan, O. Dargan, W. Dargan, Dario (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Dauban, D'Augès, Davenport, Davey (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - David, Davidman, D. Davidson, E.C. Davidson (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - E.G. Davidson, G. Davidson, L.J. Davidson, William Wallace Davidson, H.A. Davies (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Mary Carolyn Davies (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - E.M. Davis, F.M. Davis, F.S. Davis, H. Davis (F.S. Davis SEE ALSO OVERSIZE) (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - H.L. Davis (Box 6, Folder 4-10)
    - J.C. Davis, J.M. Davis, L. Davis, M.W. Davis (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - E. Davison, H.J. Davison (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - W. Davison, Dawes, G.S. Dawson, M. Dawson, M.M. Dawson, Day, Dawson, Scott (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - R.M. Deacon, W.A. Deacon, De Acosta, Deakin (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Dean, De Berniere, De Bosis, De Braganca, De Bullet, De Cambrey, De Casseres, De Castro, De Celles (De Bosis SEE ALSO OVERSIZE) (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Miriam Allen De Ford (Box 6, Folder 16-18)
    - De Fosset, De Garis, De Garmo, Dehner, Deis (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - David Cornel De Jong (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Delaney, De la Selva, De Laughter, Del Bittner, De Leeuw, Deluca (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Del Val, De Montalk (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - De Mouvel, De Nair, Denby, Denlinger, Dennen, Denney (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Depew, Derezinska, Derleth, Der Srabian, Deschere, Deschin, Detmers, Dewar (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - L.B. Dexter, T.N. Dexter, Diamondstein, Dick, Dickey, Dicks, Didier, Dickson, Sperling (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Dieck, Dielman, Dilke, Dilla, Diller, Dilling (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - George Dillon (SEE ALSO OVERSIZE) (Box 6, Folder 27-30)
    - J. Dillon, Dilworth, Dimorier, Dine, Dismorr (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - D. Dixon, W. Dixon, Dobbs, Dobo, Disney, Roebuck (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Lee Wilson Dodd (Box 6, Folder 33-34)
    - A.A. Dodge, M. Dodge, Dogge (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Nathan Haskell Dole (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Dollinger, Dolson, Donahay, E. Donaldson, Z. Donaldson, Donnelly, Donthat, Donvalac (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - D'Orge, Dormer, Doro, Dorset, Dos Passos, Doubs, Doughty, I. Doughty (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - L. Doughty, L.S. Doughty (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - I. Douglas, M. Douglas, P.H. Douglas, A. Dow, D. Dow, E.M. Dow (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Dowd, Dowell, Dowling, H. Downey, J.E. Downey, Downing, A. Doyle, C. Doyle (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - J.H. Doyle, M. Doyle, M.A. Doyle (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Drag, A.H. Drake, C.C. Drake, W.A. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Dransfield, E.F. Draper, G.V. Draper (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Glenn Ward Dresbach (Box 7, Folder 8-13)